-= 圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品 =-
南宫长风 作品
hd.cnscg.com
双字幕&后期：鱼子酱
小鬼当家2: 玩转纽约
我的高尔夫球呢?
Where are my golf balls?
谁见到我的太阳油?
Anyone seen my sun block?
去佛罗里达还搽什么太阳油
What's the point of going to Florida if you use sun block?
我已准备晒得一身古铜色
I don't care, I'm getting toasted.
好极了! 你一定可以晒成黑碳
Great. Now you can be a skag with a darker shade of skin.
他不能晒太阳所以妒忌 他已经满脸都是雀斑
He's jealous because he can't tan. His freckles just connect.
不要喝那么多汽水 尿片都已收好
Hey, hey, easy on the fluids! The rubber sheets are packed.
域琪 她说要"叮"
She wants "Ding. "
"叮"的后面是... 两百分
Behind "Ding" is 200 points!
二百分! 好极了
200 points! All right!
亲爱的 你准备好了吗?
Honey, are you packed yet?
好了
Yes.
要我帮你放到外面吗?
Everything I put out for you?
好的
Yes.
你知道这次旅行祖母送你什么
Oh, did you see what Grandma sent you?
我猜猜看 唐老鸭拖鞋?
Let me guess. Donald Duck slippers?
差不多
Close.
可以在水里玩的充气小丑
Inflatable clown to play with in the pool.
真令人兴奋
How exciting.
为什么去佛罗里达? 佛罗里达没有圣诞树
Why Florida? There's no Christmas trees in Florida.
圣诞树那么重要吗?
What is it with Christmas trees?
圣诞节怎可以没有圣诞树
How can you have Christmas without a Christmas tree?
我们可以用假树或椰树装饰
We'll find a nice fake silver one. Or decorate a palm tree.
"叮当咚"节目的来宾 入住纽约最有名的
Guests of Ding, Dang, Dong stay at the world-renowned Plaza Hotel:
广场酒店
New York's most exciting hotel experience.
订房致电 1800759...
For reservations, call toll-free, 1-800-759...
- 摄录机的电池在哪里? - 在充电器里
- Where's the camcorder battery? - I put it in the charger.
这样如何?
How's this?
好看多了
Oh, much better.
凯文 你最好快戴上领带 我们不想去圣诞晚会迟到
Kevin, put your tie on. We'll be late for the Christmas pageant.
我的领带在浴室 我不能进去 因为法兰叔叔在洗澡
It's in the bathroom. I can't go in. Uncle Frank's taking a shower.
他说若我进去看见他的裸体
He says if I walk in there and see him naked,
我长大后会觉得自己不像真正男人
I'd never feel like a real man.
不知道他是什么意思
Whatever that means.
他肯定是在开玩笑 你只要跑进去拿你的领带
I'm sure he was kidding. Just run in and get your tie...
不要看他赶快出来就可以
...get out, and don't look at anything.
好
Well
他们说的那只猫不知道是谁
This cat they're talking about I wonder who, could it be
我是最肥的一只猫 你从没见过这样肥的猫
'Cause I know I'm the heaviest cat The heaviest cat you ever did see
当他们看到我在街上走
When they see me Walkin ' down the street
所有傻佬都鸦雀无声
None of the fellas want to speak Hey, hey, hey
他们的脸上充满笑容
On their faces they wear a silly smirk 'Cause they know
因为他们知道我最型
I'm the king Of the cool jerks
你这偷窥狂快滚出去
Get out of here, you pervert, or I'll slap you silly!
"圣祖罗学校"
"圣诞晚会 今晚七点"
圣诞树 我的圣诞树
Christmas tree My Christmas tree
闪耀如星光
Lit up like a star
当我看见圣诞树
When I see My Christmas tree
我的亲人就在近处
Can loved ones be far
圣诞树让我肯定
Christmas tree I'm certain
无论我在何处流浪...
Wherever I roam
凯文要独唱了 告诉莉斯
Kevin's solo's coming up. Tell Leslie.
凯文要独唱了 告诉法兰
Kevin's solo's coming up. Tell Frank.
好 法兰
Okay. Frank.
...法兰?
Frank!
圣诞节即是欢乐
Christmastime means laughter
在雪中乘雪橇滑行
Toboggans in the snow
红润着脸庞
Caroling together
齐声高歌圣诞颂...
With faces aglow
凯文!
Kevin!
各陪审团成员
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
我要为我的行为所引起的不快
...I'd like to apologize for whatever displeasure...
- 向我的家人道歉 - 什么?
- ...I might have caused you. - What?
我的行为是不成熟且不适当的
My prank was immature and ill-timed.
不管是否不成熟 这恶作剧很有趣
Immature or not, it was pretty darn hilarious.
同时我也要向弟弟道歉
I also apologize to my brother.
凯文...
Kevin.
对不起
I'm sorry.
巴斯...
Oh, Buzz...
真是太好了
that was very nice.
凯文 你有话要说吗?
Kevin, do you have something to say?
你可以扮得更真诚吗? 死仔
Beat that, you trout-sniffer.
我不会道歉! 我那样做全是因为巴斯让我难堪...
I'm not sorry. I did it because Buzz humiliated me.
他可逃避一切责任 我无话可说
He gets away with everything, so I got him.
既然你们笨到相信他的谎话
Since you stupidly believe his lies...
我也不理会是否破坏佛州之旅
...I don't care if your Florida trip is wrecked.
谁要到热带过圣诞节
Who wants to spend Christmas in a tropical climate?
凯文!
Kevin!
若你这样的话 你便上三楼睡觉
You walk out, you sleep on the 3rd floor.
好 跟我睡
Yeah, with me.
你们还有新招吗?
So, what else is new?
你最好别破坏我的旅行 你爸付出了很多钱的
Don't wreck my trip. Your dad's paying good money for it.
我才不会破坏你的旅程 贪便宜到死
Wouldn't want to spoil your fun, Mr. Cheapskate.
麻烦的年青人
What a troubled young man.
他们全都是衰人
They're all a bunch of jerks.
嘿
Hi.
你记得上次旅行的时候 一开始也是这样
Last time we tried to take a trip, we had a problem just like this.
是 都是针对我的
Yeah, with me getting crapped on.
不管你怎么说 上次没针对你
I don't care for your choice of words. That's not what happened.
何况巴斯已经向你道歉
Buzz apologized to you.
对 他还叫我死仔
Yeah, then he called me a trout-sniffer.
他不是真心道歉 他只想欺骗你们
He didn't mean it. He was just sucking up to you.
好吧 你在这里好好想清楚
Okay, why don't you just sit up here and think things over?
你准备好道歉时 你就可以下来
When you're ready to apologize to everyone, you can come down.
我不会向巴斯道歉 我宁愿去死!
I'm not apologizing to Buzz. I'd rather kiss a toilet seat!
那你就在这里过夜!
Then stay up here all night.
反正我也不想下去! 全家没有一个人可信任
I don't want to go down anyway! I can't trust anybody in this family.
假如我自己有钱 我会一个人去度假
You know what? If I had my own money, I'd go on my own vacation.
独自一人 不要有你们任何人 那我就自由自在开心快活
Alone, without any of you. And I'd have the most fun of my whole life.
去年你的愿望实现了 也许今年又会应验
You got your wish last year. Maybe you will this year.
希望如此
I hope so.
芝加哥太阳时报
水喉大盗趁监狱骚动脱逃
"机场快车"
- 我们又睡过头! - 我们再次做到了
- We did it again! - We did it again!
我们家坐第一辆 其余的坐第二辆
Our McCallisters here, other McCallisters there.
我不该对免费旅行不满 但你们实在太晚叫人起床
I shouldn't complain, but you give the worst wake-up calls.
- 机票在你那里吗? - 在我这儿 这是你的
- Do you have the tickets? - I've got them. Here's your family's.
- 你有几张? - 七张
- How many do you have? - Seven.
- 七张! - 十四张!
- We have seven. - 14!
七 八 九 十
Seven...eight...nine, ten.
怎么全都是分开坐
How come we're not sitting together?
在这旺季可以搭同一班飞机 已经很好了
This time of year, we're lucky to get on the same plane.
十一 十二 十三
11, 12, 13.
凯文呢?
Where's Kevin?
十四
14.
我自己拿着机票比较好 免得你们又撇下我
Good thing I have my own ticket, just in case you try to ditch me.
- 快点 - 我要电池
- Come on. - I need batteries.
我袋里有电池 上机后给你
I'll give them to you on the plane.
- 还有两件行李 - 为什么现在不能给我?
- Here's two more. - Why not now?
等等吧 在几号闸口登机?
Not now! What's the gate number?
是H-17
H-17.
最好走快点 登机闸口在最后的地方
Better hurry, it's the last gate.
爸 几号登机门?
Dad, what gate is it?
H-17 巴斯 来吧
H-17, Buzz. Come on, Kevin.
凯文 你拿我的袋吗?
Kevin, you gonna take my bag? Take my bag.
快点
Come on. Come on.
美国航空公司飞往纽约的226号班机
American Airlines flight 226 to New York...
即将起飞
...is now in the final boarding process.
快呀 快呀!
Come on. Come on!
爸 等一等!
Dad, wait up!
爸 等等我!
等等我!
Wait up!
等等!
Wait!
快点
Come on come on!
爸 等等!
Dad, wait!
到了 就是这里!
Here we are! Here!
我们来了
We made it.
全部到齐? 我们赶到了? 好极了
Everybody here? We made it? All right.
拜托 要登机了 飞机准备要起飞了
Please board, the plane's leaving.
我想确定大家都上了飞机
I'll make sure everyone gets on.
所有人都会上飞机的
We'll get everyone on.
圣诞快乐 旅途愉快
Merry Christmas. Have a nice flight.
- 再见! - 再见!
- Bye. - Bye-bye.
嘿 等一等!
Hey wait up!
等等我!
Hey, guys, wait for me!
- 差点就赶不及了 - 对不起
- Cutting it kind of close. - Yes.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
爸 等一等!
Dad Wait!
等一下!
Wait!
- 对不起 - 没关系 你是搭这班机的吗?
- I'm sorry. - That's okay. Are you on this flight?
是的 我全家都已经上了机
Yeah. My family's on the plane.
我不想一人被留下
I don't want to be left here.
- 你有登机证吗? - 就在...
- Do you have a boarding pass? - Somewhere...
准备起飞了
They're ready to go.
他掉了登机证
He dropped his pass.
去年我也是被留下 差点毁了我的圣诞节假期
This happened to me last year and almost wrecked my Christmas.
你肯定你家人在机上
You sure your family's onboard?
我撞到这位女士前 我爸刚进去
My dad ran in right before I bumped into this lady.
让他登机 但要确保他找到家人
Board him. Make sure he locates his family before you leave him.
好的 来吧
Okay. Come on.
看到你家人吗?
Do you see your family?
我爸在那里
There's my dad.
- 去找个空位坐 圣诞快乐 - 也祝福你!
- Find an empty seat. Merry Christmas. - You too.
飞机即将起飞
In order to push back from the gate...
请各位系好安全带
...all passengers must have their seat belts fastened.
你去过佛罗里达吗?
So have you ever been to Florida?
(法语)
欢迎搭乘美国航空 第176班机直飞纽约
Welcome aboard American Airlines flight 176 non-stop to New York.
差点以为赶不上
I didn't think we'd make it.
有什么不对劲吗?
Something wrong?
亲爱的?
Honey?
我有那种感觉
I have that feeling.
我们忘了什么吗?
We forgot something?
不 我想我们没忘什么 但我...只是有那种感觉
No, I don't think we did, but I just have that feeling.
只是惨痛的回忆罢了
Just bad memories.
我们该做的都做了 该带的也带了 大家都到齐了
We did everything, brought everything. We have everybody.
还有什么好担心
There's nothing to worry about.
是 是 你说的对 你说的对 一切顺利
Yeah. Yeah, you're right. You're right. We're fine.
没什么好担心
Nothing to worry about.
妈?
Mom?
爸?
Dad?
法兰克叔叔
Uncle Frank?
巴斯?
Buzz?
全部人都下机了
We're the last ones off the plane.
他们去了哪里?
Where are those guys?
"迈阿密国际机场"
- 这是谁的? - 是布克的
- Whoes's this? - It's Brooke's.
这是米根的? 把这给布克
Is this Megan's? Give this to Brooke.
- 这是凯文的 - 把这个...把这给凯文
- This to Kevin. - Give this... Give this to Kevin.
- 把这给凯文 - 把这给凯文
- Give this to Kevin. - Give this to Kevin.
- 凯文 - 把这给凯文
- Kevin. - Give this to Kevin.
- 把这给凯文 - 把这给凯文
- Give this to Kevin. - Give this to Kevin.
- 把这给凯文 - 凯文 是你的
- Give this to Kevin. - Here you go, Kevin.
- 凯文不在这儿 - 凯文不在这儿
- Kevin's not here. - Kevin's not here.
凯文不在这儿
Kevin's not here.
什么?!
What!
凯文
Kevin!
对不起 我有紧急事件!
Excuse me, this is an emergency!
是的 先生?
Yes, sir?
那里是什么城市?
What city is that?
是纽约
That's New York.
天 我又出事了!
Yikes, I did it again!
有什么事呢 先生?
Something wrong, sir?
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
我的家人在佛罗里达 而我在纽约
Oh, no. My family's in Florida and I'm in New York.
我的家人在佛罗里达?
My family's in Florida?
而我在...纽约?
I'm in...New York?
"机场保安室"
孩子叫什么名字?
What's the child's name?
凯文
Kevin. K-E-V-I-N
你们最后什么时候见过他?
When did you see him last?
在登机舱门边?
Curbside check-in?
不 我在大门见过他 他跟着我们跑过通道
No, I saw him at the door. He was with us in the terminal.
许多人在保安检查时失散 每个人都通过保安吗?
Most people get separated at security. Did everyone get through security?
我不清楚 彼得...
I don't know. Peter...
我们那时很赶时间 我们一直跑到登机闸口
We were in a hurry. We ran all the way to the gate.
你们什么时候发现不见他?
When did you notice he was missing?
当我们在提取行李时
When we picked up our baggage here.
- 这孩子试过离家出走吗? - 没有
- Has the boy ever run away from home? - No.
他试过独自生活吗?
Has he ever been in a situation on his own?
事实上 这种事以前发生过
As a matter of fact, this has happened before.
快要变成麦家的旅行传统
It's becoming a McCallister family travel tradition.
好笑的是 我们从未不见行李
Funnily enough, we never lose our luggage.
去年他意外地被留在家里
He was left at home, by accident, last year.
这就是我太太所说家族传统的由来
That's what my wife meant calling it a McCallister family travel tradition.
我们会通知芝加哥注意此事
We'll call Chicago and...notify them of the situation.
他很有可能还在那里
The odds are that's where he is.
谢谢
Thanks.
他应该不会去了别的地方
Very unlikely he'd be anywhere else.
小心
Watch out, kid!
"新鲜海产"
你的载货单呢?
Yo, where's your manifest?
我们到了 马夫 纽约都会 机会之都
Here we are, Marv, New York City. The land of opportunity.
闻到吗?
Smell that?
恩
Yeah.
你知道那是什么?
Know what that is?
- 鱼腥味? - 是自由
- Fish. - It's freedom.
不 是鱼
No it's fish.
- 是自由 和财富 - 好吧 好吧 是自由
- It's freedom and it's money. - Okay, okay. It's freedom.
来吧 不要被人发现
Come on, let's go before someone sees us.
是鱼腥味
And it's fish.
我弄了两个假护照
Yes, one quick score.
我们可以远走他乡
We get ourselves some phony passports...
我们拼命逃走到一些外国的国家
...and we hightail it to some foreign country.
到亚里桑那州?
Arizona?
你真聪明 马夫
That's very smart, Marv.
你逃狱出来就只为了偷圣诞老人十几仙?
You bust out of jail to rob 14 cents from a Santy Claus?
聊胜于无
Every bit helps.
而且我们可以有新外号
Besides, now we got our new nickname.
我们叫"粘匪"!
We're the Sticky Bandits!
真可爱
Real cute.
Very cute.
广场酒店 纽约最好的酒店
"The Plaza Hotel. New York's most exciting hotel experience. "
变态!
Sick!
什么事?
What's the matter?
我好像看到谁
Thought I saw something.
(法语)
找死! 走吧!
Serves you right! Come on, let's go.
我想她喜欢我
I think she likes me.
"广场酒店"
对不起 请问大堂在哪里?
Excuse me, where's the lobby?
- 走廊尽头 转左 - 谢谢
- Down the hall and to the left. - Thanks.
"叮当咚"节目的来宾
Guests of the new Celebrity Ding-Dang-Dong...
入住纽约最有名的
...stay at the world-renowned Plaza Hotel:
广场酒店
New York's most exciting hotel experience.
订房致电
For reservations, call toll-free...
1-800-759-3000
1-800-759-3000.
就这么办
I'll do just that.
你好 我是彼得·麦嘉利士打 我是家长
Howdy-do. This is Peter McCallister. The father.
我要订一间房
I'd like a hotel room.
要有特大号床 电视 和可上锁的小冰箱
With an extra-large bed, a TV...and one of those little refrigerators with a key.
信用卡? 没问题
Credit card? You got it.
广场酒店订房部 有什么可以帮你?
Plaza Reservations, may I help you?
你好 我是彼得·麦卡利斯特
Howdy-do. This is Peter McCallister.
我是家长
The father.
- 是的 先生 - 我要订一间房好的
- Yes, sir. - I'd like a hotel room.
要有特大号床 电视
With an extra-large bed, a TV...
和可上锁的小冰箱
and one of those little refrigerators with a key.
入住登记时请出示信用卡
You'll need a major credit card.
信用卡? 没问题!
Credit card? You got it.
谢谢 希望令你宾至如归
Thank you. Enjoy your stay.
是的 八点两位 是山本先生
Yes, two at eight, Henri. Mr. Yamamoto.
等一下
Hold on a second.
我一会儿再打给你
I'll call you back.
嗨
Hi.
我可以为你服务吗?
Can I help you?
麦卡利斯特订的房
Reservation for McCallister.
你自己住的?
A reservation for yourself?
我的双脚都快离地才够得到柜台
My feet are hardly touching the ground.
你看我这么年少
I can barely see over the counter.
我怎可以自己订房?
How can I make a reservation for a room?
你用脑想一想 我一个小孩来酒店
Think about it: A kid going into a hotel making a reservation?
我不认为是这样
I don't think so.
我不是太明白
I'm confused.
我跟爸爸一起外出 他是来谈生意 正在开会
I'm traveling with my dad. He's on business. He's at a meeting.
我讨厌开会 况且我也不能参加会议 我只能坐在大堂
I hate meetings. I'm not allowed to go in, only to sit in the lobby.
十分无聊
That's boring.
所以我爸爸叫我先来这里
So my dad dropped me off.
给我这张信用卡 他说负责登记的人
Gave me his credit card and said to have check-in...
会让我上酒店房间 那样我就不会受伤害
...let me in the room so I won't get into mischief.
有时我真的很容易受伤害
Ma'am, sometimes I do get into mischief.
我们全都是这样
We all do.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
没有他的消息
No sign of him.
有消息会通知你们 你们订了酒店吗?
We'll need to be in touch. You have hotel rooms?
- 订了 - 你们有他的近照吗?
- Yeah. - Do you have a recent photo of him?
我钱夹里有一张
I have one in my wallet.
钱夹不在我这儿
I don't have my wallet.
我的钱夹在背袋里
My wallet's in my bag.
凯文在机场找过我的袋 凯文带着我的钱夹
Kevin was looking in my bag at the airport. He has my wallet.
- 钱夹里有信用卡吗? - 信用卡 还有钱...
- Did you have credit cards? - Credit cards, money...
我们马上联络信用卡公司
We'll notify the credit card companies.
假定你儿子拿着信用卡 只要他用的话便知道他在哪里
If your son has the cards, we can get a location on him when he uses them.
我想凯文不懂用信用卡
I don't think he knows how to use a credit card.
真的可以
Wow! It worked!
- 思治 - 是
- Cedric. - Yes?
- 不要在公共场所数你的小费 - 对不起!
- Don't count your tips in public. - I'm sorry.
去查探一下那小孩
And find out everything you can about that young fellow.
请到柜台!
Front, please!
欢迎入住我们酒店
Enjoy your stay with us.
别忘了告诉你爸爸
Don't forget to remind your dad, when he arrives...
等他来了让他来签个字
he must come down and sign a couple of things.
谢谢 你非常帮忙
Thank you, you've been helpful.
我可以帮你拿吗?
May I take your bag?
是这里 左边
Up here to your left.
胡佛曾经住过这层
Herbert Hoover once stayed on this floor.
你是说清洁人员?
The vacuum guy?
不 是美国总统
No, the president.
这是我们最好的套房之一
This is one of our finest suites, sir.
棒极了!
This is great!
我一个人睡这么大的床!
Wow! A huge bed just for me!
又豪华 又宽敞
Luxurious and spacious.
好方便!
How convenient.
嘿
Hey.
钥匙要放在袋里 还是要自己拿着?
Did you want the key in the bag? Or did you want to hang on to it?
我自己拿
I'll hang on to it.
一切满意吗?
Everything all right?
- 房间的温度适合吗? - 很好
- Is the temperature okay? - It's okay.
- 你知道怎么用电视吗? - 我十岁了 电视是我的生命
- Do you know how the TV works? - I'm 10 years old. TV's my life.
好吧
Well
对不起
I'm sorry.
不够的话 我还有很多
And there's plenty more where that came from.
谢谢
Thank you.
我跳水会影响你们吗?
Would you mind if I worked on my cannonballs?
没问题
No.
谢谢
Thanks.
这才叫度假
This is a vacation.
站在那里!
Hold it right there!
是我 庄尼
It's me, Johnny.
我知道是你 你一出电梯我就闻到
I knew it was you. I could smell you getting off the elevator.
两球吗 先生?
Two scoops, sir?
两球? 来三球吧 我不赶时间
Two? Make it three, I'm not driving.
- 庄尼 你最爱的田园香味 - 谢了
- Gardenias, Johnny, your favorite. - Thank you.
你昨晚也在这儿吧?
You was here last night too, wasn't you?
我昨晚在蓝猴子演唱
I was singing at the Blue Monkey last night.
她没有 她和你弟弟鬼混
She was not. She was smooching your brother.
你昨晚在这儿和我兄弟鬼混
You was here and you was smooching with my brother.
- 看吧? - 根本不是真的
- See? - That's a dirty lie.
你不用解释 你跟每个人都有一手
Don't give me that. You been smooching everybody!
史纳菲 艾尔 里奥...
Snuffy, Al, Leo...
我可以一直数下去
I could go on forever, baby.
你完全误会我了!
You have me all wrong!
好吧
All right...
我相信你
...I believe you.
但我的机枪不信
But my Tommy gun don't!
庄尼!
Johnny!
你是我唯一的男人
You're the only duck in my pond!
你跪下来 说你爱我
Get down on your knees and tell me you love me.
宝贝! 你是我的一切
Baby! I'm over the moon for you!
你这样不够
You gotta do better than that!
假如我对你的爱是海洋 没有飞机可以飞越这海洋
If my love was an ocean, Lindy'd have to take two planes to get across it.
也许我一时胡涂 但我相信你
Maybe I'm off my hinges, but I believe you.
所以我给你时间走
That's why I'm letting you go.
我会数到三
I'm gonna give you till the count of three,
给你这贱人滚出去
to get your lousy...lying...lowdown, four-flushing carcass out my door!
她的确是贱妇
She's rat bait.
一!
One!
二!
Two!
三!
Three!
圣诞快乐! 畜牲
Merry Christmas, you filthy animal.
还有 新年快乐!
And a Happy New Year.
房间服务
Housekeeping.
我们识得有个型仔
We know a guy who can do the cool jerk
他们说的那只猫是谁
This cat they're talkin ' about
我是最肥的一只猫
I wonder who could it be
因为我知道我是最重的猫
'Cause I know I'm the heaviest cat
你从没见过这样胖的猫
The heaviest cat you ever did see
当他们看到我在街上走
When they see me Walkin ' down the street
所有傻佬都鸭雀无声
None of the fellas want to speak Hey, hey, hey
他们的脸上充满笑容
On their faces they wear a silly smirk 'Cause they know
因为他们知道我最棒
I'm the king of the cool jerks
你这偷窥狂快滚出去!
Get out of here, you pervert, or I'll slap you silly!
我们蜜月时也比这好
Didn't look this bad on our honeymoon.
罗拔叔叔原来住在纽约
Uncle Rob lives here.
假如他们从巴黎回来 我便去拜访他们
If they're back from Paris, I'll drop in on them.
他们常送很好的礼物
They usually give pretty good presents.
晚安 妈
Good night, Mom.
晚安 凯文
Good night, Kevin.
你的内裤 先生
Your drawers, sir.
你怎可拿着这个到处走 这里可能有女孩在呀
Don't flash these babies around here! There could be girls on this floor!
我很小心的 先生
I was very careful, sir.
拿着内衣裤再小心也没用
You can't be too careful with underwear.
是的
I understand.
对不起 忘了你想要的小费
I'm sorry. You wanted a tip.
不必了 昨天的还有剩
That won't be necessary, sir. I still have some tip left over.
不要小费?
No tip?
好吧
Okay.
不 不 等等! 等等!
No, no, wait, wait, wait, wait!
招待会帮您叫的士
The doorman will be happy to find you a taxi...
麦先生
Mr. McCallister.
对不起
Excuse me.
没问题
Sure.
今早的服务如何?
And how are we this morning?
- 很好 我的车准备好了吗? - 就在大门 先生
- Fine. Is my transportation here? - Out in front, sir.
豪华轿车和...比萨
A limousine and a pizza.
广场酒店赠送的
Compliments of the Plaza Hotel.
我希望你父亲明白 昨晚
I do hope your father understands that last night...
我只是去检查房间 以确定一切就绪
...I was simply checking to see that everything was in order.
他十分生气
Oh, he was pretty mad.
他是很生气
He was?
他来纽约不是要来脱给人看
He said he didn't come here to have his naked rear spied on.
当然不是...
Of course not.
他马上会下来吗?
Will he be down soon?
他已经出去了
He already left.
我想亲自向他道歉
I would've liked to have offered my personal apology.
假如有人偷看你洗澡 你会想见他吗?
If a guy saw you in the shower, would you want to see him?
我想不会
I suppose not.
我想你是不会再见到他
I don't think you'll see him again.
是的
I understand.
再见
Bye.
希望你玩得高兴
Have a lovely day.
麦卡利斯特!
McCallister...
"处理中"
- 早安 麦先生 - 早安
- Good morning, Mr. McCallister. - Morning.
麦先生 你的...芝士比萨
Mr. McCallister, here's your very own...cheese pizza.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello? - Hello.
这里有好的玩具城吗?
Know any good toy stores?
当然有
Yes, sir.
"被偷"
果然!
Bingo!
出去 滚出去
Get outta here! Go on get outta here! Get outta here!
走开! 走开!
Beat it! Beat it! Get outta here!
马夫! 过来! 我有话说!
Hey, Marv! Get over here! I gotta talk to you!
哇哦
Whoa whoa!
- 你要领巾吗? - 别理领巾吧 我们有事要谈
- Would you like a scarf? - Forget about that, we gotta talk.
现在我们没办法做大单的 像银行 珠宝店
We don't have the equipment to pull off anything big: Banks, jewelry stores...
我们不要货物 我们要现金 现在就要
We don't want goods. We need cash and we need it now.
酒店可以吗?
How about...hotels?
游客常带着大量现金
Tourists carry lots of cash.
我有更好的主意 圣诞前夕商店的现金 不能存入银行
I got a better idea. Stores ain't depositing cash on Christmas Eve.
通常有大量现金的 都是卖中价货的店
The stores that will have cash are the ones dealing in moderate priced goods.
对 对
Right. Right.
什么店圣诞前夕有大量现金
Ergo, what store's gonna make the most cash on Christmas Eve...
而没有人会想到去抢?
...that nobody's gonna rob?
糖果店
Candy stores.
九岁小孩才会抢糖果店 这是我选中的店
Nine-year-olds rob candy stores. This is what I had in mind:
"邓肯玩具城"
真聪明! 真聪明
That's brilliant, Harry! Brilliant!
没有人会笨到 在圣诞前夕洗劫玩具城
Nobody's dumb enough to knock off a toy store on Christmas Eve.
有的 就是...
Oh, yes, there is.
我们到了 邓肯玩具城
Here we are, sir: Duncan's Toy Chest.
圣诞快乐 凯文
Merry Christmas, Kevin.
这是意外走失的意外收获
This is the greatest accident of my life.
"圣诞老人工作坊"
马夫 马夫
Marv. Marv!
好房子 但没有厕所
Hey, nice house. But there's no bathroom in it.
我们的计划怎样?
So, what's the plan?
等大家都离去后 我们就从小屋走出来
Everyone leaves for a holiday off. We come out of our houses.
是 然后呢?
Yeah, then what?
我们把收银机的钱全拿走 然后大摇大摆走出去
We empty the registers and walk out.
完美的计划!
Great plan, Harry!
多谢 圣诞快乐
Well, now, thank you and Merry Christmas.
代我向您家人问好
Say hello to the family.
让我看看
Let me see.
你一个人来买东西?
You shopping alone?
在纽约? 我想我是一个人
In New York? Sir, I'm afraid of my own shadow.
- 我只想确认一下 - 您真负责任
- I was just checking. - That's very responsible of you.
谢谢
Oh, well, thank you.
不用谢
My pleasure.
总共是23元75分
That'll be $23.75.
你为什么那么多钱?
My, my, my. Where did you get all that money?
- 我有很多祖母 - 哦
- I have a lot of grandmothers. - Oh.
那就是了
Well, that explains it.
这间店真好 是我去过最好的玩具城
This is a nice store. One of the finer toy dealerships I've visited.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
邓肯先生一定是个很好的人
Mr. Duncan must be a nice guy...
让所有的小朋友都能进来这里玩玩具
...letting kids come in here and play with his toys.
大部份玩具城都不这样做
Most toy stores prohibit that.
- 真的? - 是的
- Is that so? - Yes.
他很喜欢小孩子
Well, he loves kids.
事实上 今天所有收入
As a matter of fact, all the money the store takes in today...
邓肯先生会捐给儿童医院
Mr. Duncan is donating to the Children's Hospital.
圣诞节后
And the day after Christmas...
我们将收银机里钱取出来
...we empty out all the money in the cash register...
邓肯先生会将钱送去医院
...and Mr. Duncan takes it right down to the hospital.
他真慷慨
That's generous of him.
孩子们带给他许多快乐
Well, children bring him a lot of joy...
就像带给所有重视孩子的人
...as they do to everyone who appreciates them.
我不该花这钱的 但我铲雪赚了二十元
I'm not supposed to spend this, but I have $20 in a jar in our garage...
放在我哥哥也找不到的地方 我可以用那钱还给我妈
...where my brother can't find it. So I can pay my mother back.
所以请把这钱给邓肯先生 医院比我更需要它
So give this to Mr. Duncan. The hospital needs it more than I do.
况且我可能乱买糖果吃坏牙齿
Besides, I'll probably spend it on stuff that will rot my teeth and mind.
那...那真是太好了
Ah, that's... That's very sweet of you.
你看到那边的树吗?
You see that tree there?
为了感谢你的慷慨
Well, to show our appreciation for your generosity...
你可选一样东西
...I'll let you select an object from that tree...
- 带回家 - 免费的?
- ...to take home with you. - For free?
- 我可以给你提议吗? - 可以
- May I make a suggestion? - Okay.
拿那对斑鸠
Take the turtledoves.
我可以拿两个?
I can have two?
是 一对斑鸠 我再告诉你怎么做
Well, "two turtledoves. " And I tell you what you do.
你留一个
You keep one...
另一个送给很特别的人
...and give the other one to a very special person.
你知道 斑鸠是友情与爱的象徵
You see, turtledoves...are a symbol of friendship and love.
只要两个人都有斑鸠 你们就永远是朋友
Now, as long as each of you have your turtledove...you'll be friends forever.
我从来都不知道 我以为它们只在歌里出现
Wow, I never knew that. I thought they were just part of a song.
没错 而且它们也为此特殊理由存在
They are. And for that very special reason.
哇
Wow.
谢谢
Thanks.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
也祝你圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas to you too.
出去时穿多点 外面很冷
Be sure to bundle up if you go outside. It's nippy.
我会的
Oh. I'll do that.
"邓肯先生肖像"
去哪里?
Well, where to?
你说带我去中央公园动物园
You promised you'd take me to the Central Park Zoo.
看那是谁
Hey, look who it is.
来 去捉他
Come on, let's get him.
你好 小朋友
Hi, pal.
快!
Come on.
嘿!
Hey!
小心点!
Hey, watch it, man!
快来买 不用跟人争 五元二串 五元二串
Buy now and avoid the Christmas rush. Two for $5. Two for $5.
十元四串
Four for 10.
他在那里!
There he is!
很好
All right.
- 谢谢 - 圣诞快乐!
- Thanks. - Merry Christmas, dude.
好极了!
Yes!
- 谢谢你的提议 - 这是我的责任 荣幸之至
- Thank you for your suggestion. - My duty. My pleasure.
救我! 有两个人在追我!
Help! There's two guys after me!
怎么回事? 商店不收你偷来的信用卡?
What's the matter? Store wouldn't take your...stolen credit card?
我们让警察来处理
Let's see what the police have to say about this.
起来! 起来!
Get up! Get up!
快 去捉他!
Come on! Let's go get him.
回来 你这小偷!
Get back here, you little thief!
捉住那小孩!
Stop that child!
捉住他!
Grab him!
你这小贱人!
You little sh...
我犯了信用卡欺罪诈
I've committed credit card fraud.
叫警卫来!
Get me security!
我们要把犯人捉住!
We've got to stop that delinquent!
来吧 思治!
Come along, Cedric!
度假完了 是时候回家
I've had enough of this vacation. I'm going home.
站在那里!
Hold it!
我是门房先生!
This is the Concierge, sir!
我知道是你
I knew it was you.
你一出电梯我就闻到
I could smell you getting off the elevator.
你昨晚也在这儿吧?
You was here last night too, wasn't you?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
我来过
I was.
你昨晚在这儿和我兄弟鬼混
You was here and you was smooching with my brother.
我恐怕您误会了
You're mistaken, sir.
你不用解释 你跟每个人都有一手
Don't give me that. You've smooched everybody.
史纳菲 艾尔 里奥...
Snuffy, Al, Leo...
还有基夫
...Cliff...
"基夫"
不!
No!
他说谎!
It's a lie!
我可以一直数下去
I could go on forever, baby.
我实在抱歉 先生 但恐怕您真的弄错了
I'm terribly sorry, sir. I'm afraid you're mistaken.
我们在找一个小孩
We're looking for a young man.
好吧 我相信你 但我的机关枪不信
All right, I believe you...but my Tommy gun don't.
你跪下来说你爱我
Get down on your knees and tell me you love me.
跪下?
On your knees.
我爱你!
I love you!
这样不够
You gotta do better than that!
我爱你!
I love you!
也许我一时胡涂 但我相信你
Maybe I'm off my hinges...but I believe you.
所以我给你时间走
That's why I'm gonna let you go.
我会数到三
I'm gonna give you till the count of three...
给你这贱人滚出去
to get your lousy, lying, low-down...four-flushing carcass out my door!
- 一! - 打开门!
- One! - Open the door!
二!
Two!
三!
Three.
圣诞快乐! 畜牲!
Merry Christmas, you filthy animal.
还有 新年快乐!
And a happy new year.
留在你们房间! 紧急事故!
Stay in your rooms! This is an emergency!
有持枪的神经客在内
There's an insane guest with a gun!
不
No!
来这儿!
Come to Papa!
迈阿密来回机票 怎么了? 搭错了飞机吗?
Round trip to Miami. What's the matter, get on the wrong plane?
看来你不再需要这个
You won't be needing this.
美国航空不一定飞到目的地 小兄弟
American don't fly to the promised land, little buddy.
来吧
Come on
我们坐了九个月监 以为我们是世上最倒霉的人
We spent 9 months in jail thinking we had the worst luck in the universe.
我们错了
We were wrong.
我们逃狱后过得很好 我们会过得更好
We busted out and we're doing fine. Even better...
因为我们不再抢住宅 我们现在要抢玩具城
...because we're not robbing houses, we're robbing toy stores.
今晚半夜我们去邓肯玩具城
At midnight tonight, we'll hit Duncan's Toy Chest.
五层楼的现金任我们拿
Five floors of cash.
我们用假护照逃到巴西
Then after that, we grab some phony passports and go to Rio.
- 闭嘴吧 - 他又不会跟别人说
- You want to shut up? - He's not gonna talk to anybody.
除了跟鱼
Except maybe a fish.
或送葬队伍说
Or the undertaker.
我们到地铁处置他 我要杀了他才安心
Let's go to the subway tunnel. I'll feel better once I get him on ice.
我袋里有枪
I've got a gun.
你敢开口便包你脑袋开花
Say anything and you'll be spitting gum out through your forehead.
你好
Well, hello.
是他!
He did it!
做什么?
Did what?
谢谢!
Thanks!
快去捉他 他跑进了公园
Go get him. He went in the park.
你在干什么?
What are you doing flirting?!
在那边!
Over there!
不要 给他
Don't! Give it!
嘿 哈利!
Hey, Harry.
- 我捉到他了! - 我看看!
- I got him. - Let me see!
不是他 放他下来 不是他
That ain't him! Put him down. That ain't him.
我们有机会便应杀了他
We should've shot him.
我讨厌拖拖拉拉 又给那小贼逃掉
I hate pulling a job, knowing that creep's loose.
- 他可以怎样? 小孩子是无助的 - 不是这个小孩
- What can he do? Kids are helpless. - Not this kid.
但这次他没有满布机关的屋
But this time he doesn't have a house full of dangerous goodies.
他是一个人在公园里 公园对小孩子来说很可怕
He's in the park. He's alone. Kids are scared of the park.
是 大人在这里也活不了
Yeah. Grown men come in the park and don't leave alive.
是呀
Yes
祝你好运 小鬼
Good luck, little fella.
我想回家
I want to go home.
妈 你在哪里?
Mom, where are you?
(西班牙语)
小声点!
Turn that down!
- 喂 - 麦女士在吗
- Hello? - Kate McCallister.
- 我是 - 我们找到你的儿子
- This is she. - We found him.
- 天! - 怎么样?
- Oh, my God! - What?
- 他们知道凯文在哪儿 - 在哪里?
- They know where Kevin is. - Where?
- 他在纽约市 - 他在纽约!
- He's in New York City. - New York!
纽约
New York?
什么?
What?
- 他一定很怕 他不是搞事的人 - 什么 什么
- He's scared, he's not a troublemaker. - What? What?
纽约的警察...
New York police officers...
请等一等 别收线
Just second! Please hold on
他用了你的信用卡 住进了广场酒店
He used your credit card to check into the Plaza Hotel.
- 他现在还在那儿吗? - 他还在那儿吗?
- Do they still have him? - Do they have him?
- 不 警察还在找他... - 该死!
- No, they're still looking. - Damn it!
- 请尽快赶去纽约 - 我们搭下班飞机去
- Get to New York. - We're on the next flight out.
谢谢 我们去纽约!
Thanks. We're going to New York, move it!
快!
Yes!
当酒店质问他信用卡时 他逃跑了 他一定很害怕
He ran away when they asked about the card. He must be scared!
- 我想他不会去找我弟弟吧? - 他们不是在巴黎吗?
- Would he go to my brother's? - Aren't they in Paris?
- 也许有人帮他们看屋 - 你不是说他们房子在装修
- Maybe they have a housesitter. - Aren't they renovating?
喂?
Hello?!
罗拔叔叔! 佐捷婶婶! 有人在家吗?
Uncle Rob! Aunt Georgette! Anybody home?!
你好
Hello!
有人在家吗? 是我... 你们最疼爱的侄子 凯文
Anybody home? It's me, your favorite nephew, Kevin!
罗拔叔叔! 佐捷婶婶!
Uncle Rob! Aunt Georgette!
小鬼 小心点!
Watch it, kid!
想听床边故事吗?
You looking for someone to read you a bedtime story?
的士!
Taxi!
外面世界真可怕
It's scary out there.
里面也不怎样好
Ain't much better in here.
我再也不要这种度假
I don't ever want to take a vacation like this again.
你们从哪儿走出来?
Where did you come from?
我不知道够不够你们吃
I don't have enough for everybody.
你们很饿吗?
How hungry are you guys?
你们把我的食物都吃光了
You guys ate all my food.
对不起 我对着你尖叫 你刚才只是想帮我 对吧?
I'm sorry I screamed in your face. You were trying to help me, right?
我叫凯文
I'm Kevin McCallister.
你的鸟儿很好
Your birds are real nice.
我见过你 你全身都是白鸽
I've seen you before. You had pigeons all over you.
第一次看到你 我觉得很恐怖 但仔细想想 也没什么可怕
At first, you look scary, but when I think about it, it's not so bad.
一定是鸽子喜欢你 才会跟着你
They must like you to be all over you.
假如我打扰你 我会离开
If I'm bothering you, I can leave.
我有否打扰你?
Am I bothering you?
没有
No.
好 是不是很麻烦?
Good. I'm not a pain in the butt?
不是
No.
白鸽会自己飞回来 还是要你叫它们回来?
Will the pigeons come back on their own or do you call them?
把手给我
Give me your hand.
它们可以听到
They can hear it.
太棒了!
This is great!
外面很冷
It's pretty cold out.
我想喝杯热朱古力 你要吗?
I'd sure like a cup of hot chocolate. How about you?
我请客
My treat.
我不喜欢在冷清的公园过圣诞前夕
I'd hate to spend Christmas Eve in such a park.
可以去温暖点的地方吗?
Can we go someplace warm?
好
Yes.
我知道一个地方
I know a place.
这音乐真动听
Nice music.
这地方真好
This place is great.
我在这里听过许多世界名曲
I've heard the world's great music from here.
你有带朋友上来吗?
Do you bring your friends here?
我的朋友不多
I haven't got many friends.
抱歉
Sorry.
我喜欢鸟儿
I'm like the birds I care for.
人们在街上与我擦肩而过 他们经过我但没看到我
People pass me in the street. They see me but they try to ignore me.
他们不当我是都市的一份子
They prefer I wasn't in their city.
对 跟我的家人一样 我就像家里被忽视的白鸽
Yeah. It's like that with my family. I'm like the pigeon of the house...
只因为我是最小的
...just because I'm the youngest.
每个人都在争斗 都希望名成利就
Everyone fights for position. Everyone wants to be seen...and heard.
我猜
I guess so.
我说太多搞太多 所以常给罚回房
I'm seen and heard pretty much. But I get sent to my room a lot too.
我以前不是这样
I wasn't always like this.
你以前是怎么样的?
What were you like before?
我有工作 我有家
I had a job. I had a home.
- 还有家人 - 你有孩子吗?
- I had a family. - Any kids?
没有 我曾经很想有孩子
No. I wanted them.
但我的爱人不再爱我了
But the man I loved fell out of love with me.
我的心被伤透
That broke my heart.
每当我有机会再被爱时
When the chance to be loved came along again...
我总是逃避
...I ran away from it.
我无法再信任别人
I stopped trusting people.
恕我直言 但那样做似乎很笨
No offense, but that seems like sort of a dumb thing to do.
我害怕再次受伤
I was afraid of getting my heart broken again.
有时候你很信任一个人...
Sometimes you can trust a person...
但一阵子他们便忘了你
...and then, when things are down, they forget about you.
也许他们只是太忙
Maybe they're just too busy.
也许他们没有忘记你 只是忘了去想起你
Maybe they don't forget about you, but they forget to remember you.
人不会故意去忘记 我爷爷说
People don't mean to forget. My grandfather says...
要不是我的头生在颈上 我可能会忘记在校车上
...if my head wasn't screwed on, I'd leave it on the school bus.
我只是害怕 假如我真的相信某人 我会再次心碎
I'm just afraid if I do trust someone, I'll get my heart broken.
我明白
I understand.
我以前有一双很美的溜冰鞋 我怕我会穿坏它
I had a nice pair of Rollerblades. I was afraid to wreck them...
所以一直放在盒子里 你猜后来怎么样?
...so I kept them in a box. Do you know what happened?
我长大了再穿不下 我一次也没穿着出外
I outgrew them. I never wore them outside.
只在房间穿过两次
Only in my room a few times.
人的心和感觉 和溜冰鞋是不一样的
A person's heart and feelings are very different than skates.
某方面都是一样的
They're kind of the same thing.
若你不再用心的话 心碎又有什么分别
If you won't use your heart, who cares if it gets broken?
假如只把心留给自己 也许会像我的溜冰鞋一样
If you just keep it to yourself, maybe it'll be like my Rollerblades.
当你想用它的时候 都已经不能用了
When you do decide to try it, it won't be any good.
你该利用机会 别再错过机会
You should take a chance. Got nothing to lose.
听起来颇有道理
Little truth in there somewhere.
我想是的 你的心也许受过伤 但还没死
I think so. Your heart might still be broken, but it isn't gone.
假如你的心已死 你不会还对人这么好
If it was gone, you wouldn't be so nice.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗 我已经... 几年没和人说话
Do you know it's been...a couple of years since I've talked to anybody?
没关系 你说得不错
That's okay. You're good at it.
你不会很无聊 不会喃喃自语和吐痰
You're not boring. You don't mumble or spit.
你该多些交谈
You should do it more often.
我想你该穿件没白鸽的衣服
Just wear an outfit with no pigeon poop on it.
我是否令其他人远离我呢?
I have been working very hard at keeping people away.
我常常想假如我独自一人 一定很好玩
I always think I'll have a lot of fun if I'm alone...
但到真的独自一人时 却一点也不好玩
...but when I'm alone, it's not fun.
我不在乎有时别人如何讨厌
I don't care how much people bug me...
我宁愿有人和我一起 也不要自己一个人
...I'd rather be with someone than alone.
那么你为什么一个人在圣诞前夕到处走
So what are you doing alone on Christmas Eve?
你惹了麻烦?
Did you get into trouble?
是的
Yeah.
你做错事?
You did something wrong?
做错很多事
A lot of things.
你知道以善抵恶吗?
Did you know that a good deed erases a bad deed?
太迟了 我不知道是否有足够时间
It's late. I don't know if I'll have enough time...
去做好事来补偿我的过错
...to do enough good deeds to erase all my bad ones.
现在正是圣诞 今晚行善会有特别优惠
It's Christmas Eve. Good deeds count extra tonight.
- 真的? - 当然是真的
- They do? - Of course they do.
好好想一想 你可以帮别人做什么事
Think of an important thing you can do for others...
而且马上就去做
...and go do it.
只要依照你心中星星指引
Just follow the star in your heart.
好的
Okay.
夜了 我要走了
It's getting pretty late. I'd better get going.
假如我没有再见到你 祝你一切顺利
If I don't see you again, I hope everything turns out okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
替我向你的白鸽说再见
Tell the birds I said goodbye.
我会的
I will.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
假如你需要找可以信任的人 你可以想到我
If you need somebody to trust, it can be me.
我不会忘记你
I won't forget to remember you.
别许下无法实践的承诺
Don't make promises you can't keep.
"圣安儿童医院"
收银机里所有的钱
All the money in the registers...
邓肯先生将全部捐给儿童医院
...Mr. Duncan is gonna donate to the Children's Hospital.
今晚午夜 我们会洗劫邓肯玩具城
At midnight tonight, we're hitting Duncan's Toy Chest.
你们可以破坏任何事
You can mess with a lot of things,
但绝不能在圣诞节欺侮小孩子
but you can't mess with kids on Christmas.
煤油
我们会为你提供一间免费套房
We'd like to offer you a complimentary suite.
是在面对公园的阁楼
It's a penthouse with a view of the park.
我想你们会感到满意
I think you'll find it satisfactory.
最近才由伯爵夫人空出来的
It was recently vacated by a countess.
这是什么酒店 居然会让一个小孩自己住宿?
What kind of hotel lets a child check in alone?
那孩子说的话跟真的一样
The boy had a very convincing story.
是什么白痴在这里工作?
What kind of idiots work here?
是纽约最好的
The finest in New York.
当你们发现信用卡报失...
When you learned the credit card...
我发现的
I made the discovery.
你为什么会让他走掉?
Why did you let him leave?
我们正想问他时 他便逃走了
We confronted him and he ran!
你把他吓跑!
You scared him!
现在是圣诞前夕 就因为你
It's Christmas Eve, and because of you,
我的孩子在最大的城市走失了
our child is lost in a huge city.
请带我们的家人和行李上房间去吧
Take our family and luggage up to the room.
是的
Yes, sir!
手脚快点 思治
Run along, Cedric.
我现在去警察局 确保他们尽全力找凯文
I'll go to the police station to make sure they're looking for Kevin.
我想你留在酒店
I want you to stay here.
- 我要出去找他 - 什么?
- I'm going to look for him. - What?
不好意思 但令郎是在最大的城市走失
With all due respect, your son is lost in one of the world's biggest cities.
请你别插嘴
Could you stay out of this?
悉随尊便
As you wish.
谢谢 我不认为你自己在纽约街头行走是好主意
Thank you. It's not a good idea to run around New York City alone.
既然我们的儿子可以 我也可以
If Kevin can, so can I.
- 基蒂 - 我不会有事的
- Kate... - I'll be fine.
我认为现在不会有强盗或杀人犯敢来惹我
The way I feel, no mugger or murderer would mess with me.
但外面有很多流泯...
There are hundreds of armed parasites out there!
穿多一点 外面非常冷
Do bundle up. It's awfully cold outside.
"邓肯玩具城"
马夫! 马夫! 来 行动吧!
Marv. Marv. Come on, let's go.
马夫? 动手橇吧!
Marv. Crowbars up!
圣诞快乐 哈利
Merry Christmas, Harry!
圣诞快乐 马夫
Happy Hanukkah, Marv!
这些钱多得数也数不完!
This is more money than I can even count!
我们以前为什么去偷住宅!
It makes you wonder why we spent so much time robbing homes.
更不可思议的是 我们是逃犯
The amazing thing is, we're fugitives from the law...
现在竟置身于钞票堆里 而没人发现
...we're up to our elbows in cash and nobody even knows about it.
他回来了!
He's back!
他拍了我们的照片!
He took our picture!
我的头发好看吗?
How was my hair?
好了 不可以回头了
This is it. No turning back.
又一次圣诞大战开始
Another Christmas in the trenches.
不!
No!
到此为止! 拿钱走!
That's it! Get the money! Get it!
我要杀了那小鬼!
I'll kill him!
- 马夫! - 我来了 哈利!
- Marv! - I'm coming, Harry!
哈利?
Harry?
哈利!
Harry!
真厉害!
That was incredible.
- 我扭到了脚! - 他在哪里?
- I twisted my ankle. - Where is he?
嘿 两位! 笑一笑!
Hey, guys! Smile!
走吧!
Come on! Come on!
- 我来扶你 - 我来扶你
- Help me. - I got you.
的士!
Taxi!
时代广场
Times Square!
他去了哪里?
Where'd he go?
我在上面 上来捉我!
I'm up here! Come get me!
我们杀上去!
Let's kill!
等等 傻瓜
Hold on, pea-brain.
我们上次低估他 所以被捕
We got busted because we underestimated that bundle of misery.
今时不同往日
This ain't like that.
这不是他家 他已经被吓坏了 他不会有什么计划
This ain't his house. The kid's running scared. He ain't got a plan.
让我先想一想 好吗?
May I do the thinking, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
小子!
Sonny!
是!
Yes?
你知道我现在最想就是杀了你
Nothing would thrill me more greatly than to shoot you.
杀一个小孩 对我来说没多大意思
Knocking off a youngster won't mean that much to me.
- 明白吗? - 恩
- Understand? - Mm-hm.
但我们在赶时间 我们来谈个交易
But since we're in a hurry, I'll make a deal with you.
你把相机抛下来 我们就不伤害你
You throw down your camera and we won't hurt you.
我们从此消声匿迹 好吗?
You'll never hear from us again. Okay?
你保证?
Promise?
我对天发誓 否则不得好死
I cross my heart and hope to die.
好吧
Okay!
来
Okay, kid...
把它给我
give it to me.
正中目标
Direct hit!
这里有几只手指?
How many fingers am I holding up?
八只?
Eight?
小鬼 你掷砖头? 来吧! 再掷一个!
Okay, kid. You want to throw bricks? Go ahead, throw another one.
别
Don't do that!
假如你没别的花样 你死定了!
If you can't do any better than that, you're going to lose.
哈利...
Harry...
不
no.
还有砖头吗?
You got any more?
起来! 他没砖头了
Get up. He don't have any more bricks.
什么?
What?
是你逼我的! 没有人向我掷砖块后 还逃得掉的! 起来!
That did it! Nobody throws bricks at me and gets away with it. Come on!
你走这边 我去后面
You go this way. I'll go around back.
哈利?
Harry?
哈利!
嗯?
Huh?
哈利!
Harry!
我到楼上了!
I reached the top!
你最好还有新花样
You better do better than this.
哇
Wow!
好大个洞!
What a hole!
哈利?
Harry.
我上来了!
I'm coming up!
我要杀了那小鬼!
I'm gonna murder that kid!
好极了!
Yes!
知道一个小孩一定胜过两个白痴吗?
Don't you know a kid always wins against two idiots?
哈利? 他在客厅!
Harry! In the living room!
他上了爬梯!
He went up the ladder!
我来了 哈利
I'm coming, Harry.
我来了
I'm coming.
哈利!
Harry!
你的牙齿没崩! 来吧 他上了二楼
You didn't lose any teeth! Come on, he went to the second floor.
嘿
Hey!
你们为什么不试试楼梯?
Try the stairs.
对
Right.
等等 等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你不记得去年怎么了吗?
Remember last year?
不记得
No.
看着
Watch this.
我们去捉他!
Let's get him!
他打中我的嘴 马夫!
He busted me right in my mouth, Marv!
第一个
That's one.
别担心 哈利...
Don't worry, Harry.
我去捉他
I'll get him.
正中我的要害
Right in the schnoz.
第二个
That's two.
来吧 我们去捉他
Come on, let's get him.
哎呀
Oops.
这是
That's...
第三个
...three.
不
No.
第四个
That's four.
- 来吧 哈利 - 马夫 这个真的安全吗?
- Come on, Harry. - Marv, are you sure this is safe?
我已经试过
I've worked all the kinks out.
如岩石一样稳固
Solid as a rock.
像岩石一样?
Like a rock, huh?
你们要不要放弃?
Give up?
- 痛得还不够么? - 绝不!
- Have you had enough pain? - Never!
你最好赶快祈祷!
You better say every prayer you ever heard!
我希望你父母圣诞节能找到坟墓
I hope your parents got you a tombstone for Christmas.
他去了哪里?
Where'd he go?
我在上面 好害怕
I'm up here and I'm really scared.
那是什么声音?
What's that sound?
那是工具柜...
That was the sound of a tool chest...
掉下楼梯的声音
falling down the stairs.
好极了!
Yes!
在那里!
Over there!
就算要坐电椅 我也要杀了那小鬼!
Even if I get the chair, I'm killing that kid!
投降吧 小鬼!
Surrender, kid!
他不见了
He vanished.
我在下面 你两个大笨蛋
I'm here, you horse's ass!
哇哦
Whoa.
恭喜你的颈受伤
Nice night for a neck injury!
接砖吧 小鬼!
Suck brick, kid!
来吧 马夫!
Come on, Marv.
我不行
I don't know.
过来
I said, come on!
来吧 娘娘腔!
Come on, you big sissy.
哈利 你用了剃须水?
Harry? You wearing aftershave?
那是火油
That's kerosene.
浸过火油绳子
The rope is soaked in it.
为什么会都把绳子浸火油?
Why would anyone soak a rope in kerosene?
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
返回上面!
Go up!
滚下来!
Get off me!
拿袋子!
Get the bag!
抢劫邓肯玩具城的两个贼在公园里
Two guys who robbed Duncan's Toy Chest are in the park.
中央公园西边 95街 留意放烟火的地方
Central Park West, 95th Street. Look for fireworks.
快点 他们有枪
Hurry, they got a gun.
我在这里
I'm here.
最好在我报警前捉住我
Better come and get me before I call the cops.
风水轮流转呀
My, how the tables have turned.
你喜欢冰吧?
How do you like the ice?
我们去公园走走
Let's go for a little stroll in the park.
把那个背袋给我
Give me the bag.
给我!
Give me it!
放到相簿应该很好看
Great for the album.
你是赢了战斗 小鬼 但你却输了战争
You may've won the battle, dude, but you lost the war.
你不该惹怒我们
You ought not of messed with us.
我们是危险人物
We're dangerous.
- 哈利? - 闭嘴!
- Harry? - Shut up!
哈利?
Harry.
闭嘴! 我要好好享受
Shut up! I want to enjoy this.
好像有点问题
Something's wrong.
- 我们快离开这儿吧 - 闭嘴!
- Let's get out of here! - Shut up!
我没读过六年级...
I never made it to the 6th grade...
看来你也读不到
...and it doesn't look like you're gonna either.
让他走!
Let him go!
凯文 快跑!
Kevin, run!
射她!
Shoot her!
- 射她! - 我也想射她!
- Shoot her! - I'm trying!
再见 谢谢
Bye! Thanks.
天 简直像国庆烟花!
Jesus, looks like the 4th of July!
我们去桥那边! 你们去隧道!
We got the bridge. Take the tunnel.
我们走 我们走
Let's go, let's go!
我的天!
Oh, my God!
好了 走吧!
All right, let's go.
来吧 起身
Come on, on your feet.
慢慢来
Take it easy!
"坏人说要杀我"
你们该早点行动 监狱囚犯已交换圣诞礼物
You guys should've started earlier. The prisoners already exchanged gifts.
我们错过了圣诞礼物?
We missed the presents?
是他要我一起藏在店里 去偷捐给小孩的钱
He made us hide in the store and steal the kiddies' charity money.
闭嘴 马夫
Shut up, Marv.
你有沉默的权利
You've got the right to remain silent.
他脾气不太好 我们刚逃狱出来不久
He's a little cranky. We just broke out of prison.
住嘴 马夫!
Shut up, Marv!
带走他们!
Get them out of here!
记住假如上报的话
If this makes the papers...
我们不再叫"水喉大盗" 我们是"粘匪"
...we're no longer the Wet Bandits, we're the Sticky Bandits.
是"粘" NIAN...
That's sticky. S...T... I. I.
案件结束了 我们捉到窃贼也找回失款
It's all over. We apprehended the thieves and got your money.
我想尽快将钱送到儿童医院
I want to get that money over to the Children's Hospital.
- 我会帮您处理 - 谢谢
- I'll handle it. - Thank you.
对不起
Excuse me.
看这字条 好像是小孩打破窗口
I found this note. Looks like a kid broke your window.
亲爱的邓肯先生
Dear Mr. Duncan:
我打破你的窗口 是为了捉坏人
I broke your window to catch the bad guys.
你有买保险吗?
Do you have insurance?
没有的话 等我回到芝加哥 我寄钱给你
If not, I'll send you some money, if I ever get home.
圣诞快乐 凯文
Merry Christmas. Kevin McCallister.
附注: 谢谢你的斑鸠
P. S. Thanks for the turtledoves.
斑鸠
Turtledoves.
对不起 我在找我儿子 就是这男孩
Excuse me. I'm looking for my son. This boy here.
拜托帮个忙 这男孩... 你见过他吗?
Please help me. This boy right here. Have you seen him?
我在找我儿子 他走失已两天
I'm looking for my son. He's been missing for two days.
- 你报警了吗? - 当然有
- Have you filed a report? - Of course we have.
那么就相信我们 我们会处理的
Then trust us. We'll handle it.
但我是他的母亲
I'm his mother.
我了解 但你这样简直是大海捞针
I know, but you're looking for a needle in a haystack.
你有小孩吗?
Do you have kids?
有
Yes, ma'am.
你会怎么做?
What if one was missing?
我可能也会跟你现在一样
I'd probably do the same thing you're doing.
谢谢
Thank you.
站在你孩子的立场想
Put yourself in his shoes.
你会去哪儿? 做什么?
Where would you go? What would you do?
我? 我可能已死在某个水沟里
Me? I'd probably be lying dead in a gutter somewhere.
但凯文不会
But not Kevin.
不 凯文比我强壮勇敢得多
No. Kevin is so much stronger and braver than I am.
我知道凯文会很好 我肯定他很好
I know Kevin's fine. I'm sure he is.
但他仍是独自一人在纽约
But he's still alone in a big city.
他不该受这样的罪
He doesn't deserve that.
他应该在家的 和自己的家人在一起 围着他的圣诞树
He deserves to be at home with his own family around his Christmas tree.
天...
Oh, dear God...
我知道他在哪里了
...I know where he is.
我得赶到洛克菲勒中心
I need to get to Rockefeller Center.
- 进来 - 谢谢
- Hop in. - Thank you.
我知道即使我做了好事 也不值得可以过圣诞节
I know I don't deserve a Christmas even if I did do a good deed.
我不要任何礼物
I don't want any presents.
相反 我想收回曾对家人说过的尖酸话
Instead, I want to take back every mean thing I ever said to my family...
即使他们不收回他们曾说过的
...even if they don't do the same.
我不在乎 我爱全部的家人 包括巴斯
I don't care. I love all of them. Including Buzz.
假如不能够再见到他们 我可不可以只见我妈?
If I can't see all of them, could I just see my mother?
我一生以后什么也不要 我只要我妈
I'll never want another thing, ever. I just want my mother.
我知道今晚见不到她
I know it won't be tonight...
但答应让我再见到她 任何时候
...but promise me I can see her again. Sometime. Anytime.
即使只有几分钟
Even if it's just once and only for a few minutes.
我只想跟她说对不起
I need to tell her I'm sorry.
凯文?
Kevin?
妈?
Mom?
灵验得真快?
That worked fast!
凯文
Oh, Kevin.
妈 对不起
Mom, I'm sorry.
我也对不起你
I'm sorry too.
圣诞快乐 妈
Merry Christmas, Mom.
圣诞快乐 宝贝
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们走吧
Let's go.
你怎知道我在这里?
How'd you know I was here?
我知道你和圣诞树分不开 而这是最大的一棵
I know you and Christmas trees, and this is the biggest.
其他家人在哪里?
Where's everyone else?
在酒店 他们也不喜欢棕榄树
At the hotel. They didn't like palm trees either.
下雪了 是早上!
Holy smokes, it's morning!
是圣诞早上 各位!
It's Christmas morning, man.
别高兴太早
Don't get your hopes up.
嗯?
Huh?
圣诞老人不会来酒店的
I don't think Santa visits hotels.
圣诞老人无所不在
Are you nuts? He's omnipresent.
他哪里都能去
He goes everywhere.
大家快起床 圣诞节到了
Wake up, it's Christmas!
妈! 爸! 圣诞节了!
Mom! Dad! It's Christmas!
它从何而来?
Where'd it come from?
妈 爸 快来看这个!
Mom! Dad! You gotta see this!
- 我的天! - 彼得!
- My gosh! - Peter!
我们没走错房间吗?
Are we in the right room?
别拆我的礼物
Don't open any of mine.
- 谁是邓肯先生? - 邓肯? 我不知道?
- Who's Mr. Duncan? - Duncan? I don't know.
各位 安静一下
Everybody calm down.
冷静!
Calm down!
好吧! 现在...
All right. Now...
假如凯文一开始没惹事
...if Kevin hadn't screwed up in the first place, again...
那我们便不会住在这么大的酒店房间
...we wouldn't be in this most perfect...
还有这么多的免费礼物
...and huge hotel room with all this free stuff.
所以...
So...
应由凯文开第一份礼物才公平
...I think it only fair that Kevin get to open the first gift.
然后我再开 接着轮到大家
Then I'll go and the rest of you and so on.
圣诞快乐 凯文
Merry Christmas, Kev.
圣诞快乐 巴斯
Merry Christmas, Buzz.
圣诞快乐 凯文
Merry Christmas, Kevin.
好啦! 圣诞快乐!
All right! Merry Christmas!
感动时间够了
Enough gooey sh...Show of emotion.
各位 拆礼物了
Everyone, let's dig in!
大家等一等! 把包装纸留下 留着明年可以再用
Everybody, save the paper. We can use it next year. And the bows.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
凯文!
Kevin!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
我有东西要给你
I got something for you.
这是什么?
What's this?
是斑鸠 我一个 你一个
It's a turtledove. I have one. You have one.
只要我们各有一个 我们就永远是朋友
As long as we each have a turtledove, we'll be friends forever.
凯文
Oh, Kevin.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我不会忘记你的 相信我
I won't forget you. Trust me.
麦先生的住房帐单
The room service bill, sir.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
真是没得说
Nice family.
对
Really.
好个圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas indeed.
爹
Davis
凯文!
Kevin!
你居然花了967元叫房间服务?!
You spent $967 on room service?!